Guide to the New York State College of Home Economics records, 1875-1979
College of Home Economics records, 1875-1979
- Series V. Student Activities
  - Resident Teaching: Miscellaneous
    - Freshmen's Breakfasts 1937-1939 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Student Organizations
    - Student Organizations - "Cornell Countryman," to 1921 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Cornell Countryman - "Domecon Doings" - 1929-1933 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Student Organizations- "Cornell Daily Sun," to 1921 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Martha Van Rensselaer Club (Winter Course) (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Frigga Fylga (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Kermis (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Freshman faculty meetings 1932-1933 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Senior Class Function Candle Lighting (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Sedowa - includes photograph; notebook (Box 21, Folder 16-17)
    - Omicron Nu (1922-1933); printed materials (Box 21, Folder 18-19)
    - Mortar Board 1934-1935 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Student Council 1924-1935 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Student Forum 1936-1937 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Home Economics Club; includes roll book (Box 21, Folder 23-24)
    - Student traditions (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Alumnae Association, beginnings 1927 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Alumnae Association 1938-1940 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Alumnae Association 1933-1937 (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Alumnae Institute 1954 (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Alumnae - geographical distribution 1937 and 1954 (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Alumnae newsletter- history of 1963-1964 (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Alumnae - occupations 1926-1964 (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - Alumnae - study of 952 alumnae 1911-1930 (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Alumnae jobs - letter regarding 1954-1955 (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - Alumnae - demand and supply home economics occupations 1956 (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Alumnae Association-Memos, Reports, Correspondence 1952-62 (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Alumnae Association-Correspondence 1963-1965 (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - "The Changing Role of Home Economics in Land-Grant Institutions"-by Helen Canoyer and Mary Wood 1962 (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - What do we know about our degree holders 1956 (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Home Economics - committees (early statements re function) (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Home Economics Counseling Service 1948, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - Home Economics - Secretary of College and placement programs 1933, 1946, 1955 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - Department of Food and Nutrition - graduate work (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Housing and Design Department (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - Graduate degrees - Household Art and Textiles and Clothing for 1949 (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - Institution Management Department (Box 21, Folder 43)
  - Textiles and Clothing - Costume Collection (Box 21, Folder 44)
  - Graduate Staff organization of the College of Home Economics
    - Organizational history, includes a note about its being disbanded, 1968, 1965; correspondence with the office of the Graduate School and Dean, chairman of the graduate staff, 1942-1948 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Graduate student lists - chairman of the graduate staff (Box 51, Folder 2-3)
    - General Home Economics minor 1958-1961 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Committee on Research and Graduate Study minutes 1931-1938 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Minutes 1937-1941 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Minutes 1941-1942 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Minutes 1942-1945 (Box 51, Folder 8-9)
    - Minutes 1945-1953 (Box 51, Folder 10-11)
    - Minutes 1953-1956 (Box 51, Folder 12-14)
    - Minutes 1956-1961 (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - Graduate scholarships including Anna Cora Smith; chairman of the graduate staff 1932-1948 (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence re English course for graduate students; chairman of the graduate staff 1942-1944 (Box 51, Folder 17)
    - Graduate staff - general correspondence 1945-1958 (Box 51, Folder 18)
    - Procedures in the College of Home Economics for dealing with applications for graduate study Spring 1948 (Box 51, Folder 19)
    - Home Economics graduate staff 1948-1950 (Box 51, Folder 20)
    - Manual of Style 1-950 (Box 51, Folder 21)
    - Graduate student seminars 1952-1960 (Box 51, Folder 22)
    - Report on graduate students and assistants -Ad Hoc Committee 1955 (Box 51, Folder 23)
    - Graduate staff 1956-1958 (Box 51, Folder 24)
    - Graduate staff 1958-1959 (Box 51, Folder 25)
    - Graduate staff 1959-1960 (Box 51, Folder 26)
    - Graduate staff, 1960-1961; graduate staff, correspondence, articles, 1961-1962; graduate staff, 1962-1963 (Box 51, Folder 27)
  - Studies of B.S. holders from the College of Home Economics in the 1960's (Box 65)
  - Honors Day 1960-1969
    - Photos-Honors Day, Special Events (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Honors Day Program - 1969 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Honors Day Program - 1968 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Honors Day Program - 1967 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Honors Day Program - 1966 and red book of photos (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Honors Day Program - 1965 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Honors Day Program - 1964 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Honors Day Program - 1963 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Honors Day Program - 1962 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Honors Day Program - 1960-61 (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - College of Home Economics--Dean's Office
    - Vocational interest forms for students (Box 83)
- Series VI. Teaching and Research
  - Child Development, Family Relations
    - The Causes and Treatment of Enuresis in the Pre-School Child 1926. An exploratory study of the relationships between the parental control and acceptance of rural children and the behavior and attitudes of the children toward their younger siblings Purnell #360 CDFR; Development of Thinking in Children, State Project #25 CDFR (Box 21, Folder 45)
    - Some aspects of Cognitive Development during Infancy and the Pre-school Years. State #32 CDFR (Box 21, Folder 46)
    - Sociological Studies of the Family, State #34 CDFR; Adult Influence and Child Behavior, State #35 CDFR; Explorations of Conceptions Expressed in Play, Fantasies and Dreams, State #41 CDFR; Family Factors in the Development of Entrepreneurial Ability, State #42 CDFR (Box 21, Folder 47)
    - Personality Factors Associated with Role Gratification in Women, State #20 Grant; Pride and Shame in Children, State #21 (CDFR) Grant; Effects upon Creativity and Family Interaction of Participation in a Creative Expression Program; State #22 (CDFR:l Grant (Box 21, Folder 48)
    - A Study-of the Practices and Values of Rural Families in Rearing Pre-school Childres Purnell #355 CDFR (Box 21, Folder 49)
    - A Study of patterns of control and acceptance in the child rearing practices of 91 rural mothers, Purnell #369 CDFR (Box 21, Folder 50)
    - Changing structure of the rural community with implications for rural programming, Purnell #389 CDFR; Family Structure and Personality Development, State #31 Grant CDFR; How Children Learn to Read, State #33 Grant CDFR (Box 21, Folder 51)
    - Cornell Studies in Social Growth: a) Springdale Project, b) Identification of Family Structure, State #3 CDFR includes progress reports, project statements, grant foundation assistantships, correspondence, U.S. Public Health Service, and Markle Foundation (Box 21, Folder 52-62)
  - Home Economics Education
    - Factors in School and Community Situations that are related to Effectiveness of High School Home Economics Programs (Home Economics Education) State #9 (Box 21, Folder 63)
    - Contributions of the High School Home Economics Program toward improved family living in the community (Home Ec. Ed.) State #13 (Box 21, Folder 64)
    - Study of Community Approach to Student Teaching (Home Ec. Ed.) U State #15; Factors Related to the Selection of College Teachers in Home Economics (Home Ec. Ed.) State #28; Measurement of Values of Home Economics Teachers, (Home Ec. Ed.) State #37; Evaluation of Senior High School Courses in Family Relationships, (Home Ec. Ed.) State #36 Grant (Box 21, Folder 65)
    - Cornell Refresher Conference for Teachers, 1948-"Work Conference on Life Adjustment Education" (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Jr. High School Homemaking Curriculum Workshop for Homemaking Teachers, 1955-at Buffalo, New York (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - An Overview of the Workshop in Curriculum Planning for Early Secondary Education in Homemaking, 1956-at Cornell (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Workshop and Field Experiences in Home Economics in Home Economics Education, 1959 - Ethelwyn Cornelius and Marjorie Swift - Cornell University (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Field Experience in Home Economics Education, 1959 - Summer Visit Reports - Ethelwyn Cornelius (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Field Experience in Home Economics Education, 1959-Summer Visit Reports - Marjorie Swift (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Overview of the Workshop in Secondary Education (with Focus on Homemaking 3) Summer Session, 1957-at Cornell (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Preplanning for the Workshop, 1957 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence concerning the Refresher Conference, 1957 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Summer Session, 1955-at Cornell (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - Workshop in Curriculum Planning for Early Secondary Education in Homemaking, 1955-Summer Session-at Cornell (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - New York State Conference for Homemaking Teachers, 1953-Registration Packet (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - New York State Conference for Homemaking Teachers, 1953 - Resource Center, Rooms, Study Groups, Evaluation (Box 87, Folder 13)
    - Conference - 1953- Publicity - Source of Audio Visual Material and the Conference Program Folder Description (Box 87, Folder 14)
    - Committee on Home Economics in Higher Education - Report, 1951-Chicago, Illinois (Box 87, Folder 15)
    - Workshop on Family Life Education, 1951 - Margaret Hutchins,Coordinator - Summer Session-at Cornell (Box 87, Folder 16)
    - Refresher Conference - Program and Registrants and material from the program, 1950- Summer Session-at Cornell (Box 87, Folder 17)
    - Refresher Conferences for Home Economics Teachers at Cornell- 1946-1949 (Box 87, Folder 18)
    - College Faculty Workshop, 1942-Albany, New York (Box 87, Folder 19)
    - New York State Conference for Homemaking Teachers - 1941-Syracuse (Box 87, Folder 20)
    - Bulletin Boards done by Home Economics Students in Trumansburg - 1964 (Box 87, Folder 21)
  - Textiles and Clothing
    - Textile Investigation 1923 (Box 21, Folder 66)
    - Study of clothing of pre-school children as it relates to their behavior and development, Purnell #350 TC and CDFR (Box 21, Folder 67)
    - Selection, Care and Management of Household Textiles, 1929-1930, Purnell TC; TC A study of performance during wear of women's and children's silk, rayon, and cotton wearing apparel fabrics, Purnell #310 TC; Consumer satisfaction with Garments as Related to characteristics of the Garments and consumer practices in selection, use, and care, Hatch Amended #159 (Box 21, Folder 68)
    - Psychology of Clothing, State #4 TC; Serviceability and care of selected materials containing Nylon, Dacron, and Acrylic Fibers, State #12 TC; Laboratory performance of new winter cottons and blends or mixtures in cleaning or laundering processes and in laundering or cleaning alternated with abrasives, State #14 TC; Comparative warmth of Blankets, State #29 TC; motivation and Satisfaction in the Selection and Use of Clothing Items, State #30 TC (Box 21, Folder 69)
  - Housing and Design
    - Space, Facility and Structural Regulations for Farm Houses in the Northeast Region, Research and Marketing #3, N.E. #7 H D (Box 21, Folder 70)
    - Determination of Housing Needs and Preferences of Families Engaged in Each Major Type of Farming in New York State, R & M #3 H & D (Box 21, Folder 71-72)
    - Study of Housing Requirement and House Improvement Practices of Rural Families in five Selected Areas of New York State, R & M #17 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Criteria for Improved Housing Design based on family living characteristics, State #10, Hatch #112, R & M #42 H & D; Basic Space Requirements in N.E. Farm Houses as Influenced by Activity Patterns, R & M #62 H & D;R & M Housing Needs of the Aged in Urban and Rural Areas, Hatch Amended #203 H & D; The Measurement of rural housing quality, Hatch Amended #204 H & D (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Criteria for design and planning of bathrooms, Hatch #252 H & D; Farm House Storage Facilities for food Commodities and Related Equipment, State #8 H & D; Home Buying and Financing Trends in Selected Urban Areas of New York State, State #28 H & D; Research in Residential Lighting, State #18 H & D; Grant; Housing Values, State #19 H & D; Grant (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence - includes reports, N.E.#7, R & M #3 (Box 22, Folder 4-8)
    - State Rural Housing Research (Grace Marin and others) (Box 22, Folder 9-13)
  - Food and Nutrition
    - Department of Nutrition Studies; state and federal projects (Box 22, Folder 14-31)
    - Correspondence 1948-57 (Box 22, Folder 32-36)
  - Household Management
    - Department of Household Management Studies; state and federal projects (Box 22, Folder 37-49)
    - Development of functional basis for kitchen designing (Box 22, Folder 50)
    - Miss Sowers' Research on Practice House 1931 (Box 22, Folder 51-53)
  - Institutional Management
    - Department of Institutional Management Studies; state and federal projects (Box 22, Folder 54-57)
  - Hotel Administration
    - Stoves and ranges project 1924 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous projects (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Projects never initiated (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Financial Reports
    - 1959-1960 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - 1945-1955 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - 1949-1950 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - 1948-1949 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - 1940-1944 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - 1937-1940 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - 1934-1937 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - 1932-1934 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - 1930-1932 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - 1926-1930 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - College of Home Economics Finance Research 1922-1924 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Annual Reports on Research 1949-1959 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Research in Progress 1922-1960 (Box 23, Folder 25-28)
  - Miscellaneous Reports
    - 1923-1926 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Memos, reports 1923-1930 (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Faculty Studies in Home Economics, 1924-29; Report on Vital Research, 1926; research problems in household economy, 1925-1926; memo - 1927 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Home Ec. Research, 1927, 1929; Research Questionnaire,1929 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Research in Foods and Nutrition, 1929-1930; Standards and Cost of Living Research Program, 1930-1940 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Study of school lunchroom work in some New York State schools, 1932; form for reporting projects, 1932; bills before Congress, 1935 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Research projects - Cornell Experiment Station, 1936; memos, 1941-1942; research agreements, 1944-1946 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Medical Advisory Committee on Food and Nutrition Research, 1946-1949; miscellaneous research materials, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Statement of Policy concerning research contracts, 1948; theses in Home Economics, 1948-1949; statement of patent policy, 1949; trends in Home Economics research, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Calendar of scheduled meetings and administrative dates 1950-1967 (Box 23, Folder 38-40)
    - Financing of research projects, 1952; memos and reports, 1953-57; contributions of research program to graduate programs, 1955; miscellaneous memos, 1955-1956 (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Home Economics at university level 1956 (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - The Forward Look in Home Economics Research, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - Report to Visiting Committee on Biological Science, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 44-45)
    - Textiles and Clothing Research (Box 23, Folder 46)
  - History of Research and College Research Committee
    - Early history or research in Home Economics; College Committee on Research to Dean Canoyer, 1959; research policies and practices, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 47)
    - Research Policy and Practice, (revised 1962); Statement of research policy and practice, 1957; Report of College Research Committee, 1953-1954; Statement of research policy, 1953; report of College Research Committee,1952-1953 (Box 23, Folder 48)
    - Report of College Research Committee 1949-1952 (Box 23, Folder 49)
    - Report of College Research Committee,1946-1949; activities and discussions of the research committee, 1947-1955 (Box 23, Folder 50)
    - College Research Committee, 1947; Committee on Research and Graduate Study, 1932-1934; History of the Research Committee, 1932; historical review of research, 1925-1937 (Box 23, Folder 51)
    - Research - committee meetings, 1950-1957 (Box 23, Folder 52-57)
    - Director of Research - correspondence 1922-1931 (Box 23, Folder 56-58)
    - Coordinator of Research in Home Economics (Catherine J. Personius) (Box 23, Folder 59)
  - Research Studies
    - Posture studies from the 1930's (Box 84)
    - Contains samples household work surverys done in Baldwin, New York in 1964 for the College of Home Economics (Box 89)
  - Farm Homemakers Use of Time (1936) - 13 volumes Genessee County
    - Batavia No. 11-114 (Volume 1)
    - Batavia No. 115-187 (Volume 2)
    - Batavia No. 190-303 (Volume 3)
    - Bergen No. 3-76 (Volume 4)
    - Bergen No. 78-171 (Volume 5)
    - Bethany No. 4-90 (Volume 6)
    - Bethany No. 95-175 (Volume 7)
    - Byron (Volume 8)
    - Pavilion No. 2-93 (Volume 9)
    - Pavilion No. 94-181 (Volume 10)
    - Stafford No. 1-108 (Volume 11)
    - Stafford No. 111-196 (Volume 12)
    - Seasonal Records from all Townships (Volume 13)
- Series VII. Extension
  - General Information
    - Early history of extension (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Extension correspondence to 1921 (including potato patriotism folder 6) (Box 24, Folder 2-10)
    - Extension policy (Box 24, Folder 11-12)
    - Extension schools (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Extension staff --- voting privilege (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Junior Extension (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Extension expense accounts - some early examples (before 1921) (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Extension teaching preparation for careers in extension (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Extension services in other states - correspondence to 1921 (Box 24, Folder 18-19)
    - Preparation of extension publications, to 1921 (Box 24, Folder 20-21)
    - Distribution, use of, and quotation from extension publications, to 1921 (Box 24, Folder 22-25)
    - Extension Publications Committee, to 1921 (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - New York State Extension Federation of 4-H Clubs (Box 24, Folder 27-28)
    - miscellaneous extension materials (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Farmers' Wives Reading Course and Clubs
    - Early history (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, to 1921 (Box 24, Folder 31-43)
    - Reading Course for Farm Home and Cornell Study Clubs; clippings (Box 24, Folder 44-47)
    - Farmers' Wives Reading Course and Clubs - testimonials, to 1921 (Box 24, Folder 48)
    - Reading Course - letters from readers (Box 24, Folder 49-53)
    - Envelopes - post cards from readers (Box 24, Folder 54-64)
    - Envelopes - post cards from readers (Box 25, Folder 1-8)
    - Reading Course testimonials on large index cards. see also: Box 46 for examples of booklets from Farmers' Wives Reading Course 1901-1940 (Box 25, Folder 9-16)
    - Reading Course for the Farm Home Reports 1903 (Box 25, Folder 17-20)
    - Problems of Extension Organization 1915-21 on (Box 25, Folder 21-24)
    - Cornell Study Clubs - Programs (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Study Clubs and Home Bureau: Rise of Home Bureau, Decline of Study Clubs (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Use of Other Communications Media
    - Early Radio Work (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - State College Radio Committee (Box 25, Folder 28-29)
    - Federal Movie of New York State College of Home Economics taken in 1947-1948 (Box 25, Folder 30-35)
    - Cooperation in state and county fairs (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Publicists and advertisers, correspondence to 1921 (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - 1939 Worlds Fair Exhibit (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - Cooperative Extension work in Colleges of Agriculture and Home Economics, "Better Living on the Farm" 1941-1943 (Box 25, Folder 39-40)
    - "Victory Special" Train, 1912-1920 - correspondence (Box 25, Folder 41)
- Series VIII. Correspondence
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and R. H. Wheeler, Extension Professor, to 1921 (Box 25, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and M. C. Burritt, Vice-Director of Extension, to 1921. (Box 25, Folder 43-48)
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose with A. R. Mann, to 1921 (Box 25, Folder 49-58)
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose with A. R. Mann, 1921 (Box 25, Folder 59-60)
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose with L. H. Bailey, to 1921 (Box 25, Folder 61-64)
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose with W. A. Stocking, to 1921 (Box 25, Folder 65)
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose with Charles Tuck, to 1921 (Box 25, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose with George A. Works, to 1921 (Box 25, Folder 67)
  - Correspondence:Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose with 5" ltr. Cornelius Betten (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose with President Schurman, to 1921 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose with Agriculture professors, to 1921 (Box 26, Folder 4-6)
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose with non-Agriculture faculty, to 1921 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence with the Hoovers (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence with Franklin Roosevelt (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence with the Roosevelts (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence with Eleanor Roosevelt, 1923-1941,n.d. (Box 26, Folder 11-23)
  - Correspondence with prominent figures (Box 26, Folder 24-25)
  - Invitations and calling cards (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (including correspondence about the death of Helen Canon; and correspondence concerning Belgium Medals of Honor-actual medals in museum collection #'s 330-338) (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Photocopies of correspondence from the Franklin D. Roosevelt Library -to/from Martha Van Rensselaer and Franklin Roosevelt and to/from Louise Stanley and the Hoovers; Also copies of Eleanor Roosevelt's column "My Day" (1926-1947) with references to Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose, 1919-1947 (Box 110)
  - Additional Correspondence
    - Martha Van Rensselaer, 1916-1931 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - Martha Van Rensselaer, 1921 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Helen Canon, 1919-1946 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - MVR and Flora Rose with Mary Henry, 1918-1921 (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - Flora Rose, 1910-1928 (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - Flora Rose, 1929-1938 (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - Flora Rose, 1940-1941 (Box 102, Folder 5)
    - Flora Rose, 1941-1947 (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - Flora Rose and interview with Flora Rose, 1950s (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence from Alumni Concerning the Appointment of a Woman Dean, 1931 (Box 102, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence concerning two Native American Students in the College of Home Economics, 1931 (Box 59)
    - Women's Positions, 1944, 1947, 1962 (Box 102, Folder 9)
    - Helen Canoyer-Correspondence and Speeches, 1956-1964 (Box 102, Folder 10)
    - Admissions Folder for a Student not Accepted, 1939 (Box 102, Folder 12)
    - Exhibition Catalog from Costume Exhibition in the College, by Elsie Frost, 1928 (Box 102, Folder 14)
- Series IX. Furnishings